Great Art Always Survives
Searching for Sugar Man is a music, documentary
film directed by Malik Bendjelloul.
Two South Africans set out to discover what happened to their unlikely
musical hero, the mysterious 1970s rock 'n' roller, Rodriguez.
Self, played by Stephen Segerman.
Self, played by Rodriguez.
Self, played by Regan Rodriguez.
Self, played by Eva Rodriguez.
Self, played by Mike Theodore.
Self, played by Dennis Coffey.
Searching for Sugar Man is a 2012 documentary film, written and directed by Malik Bendjelloul, which details the efforts in the late 1990s of two Cape Town fans, Stephen "Sugar"
Segerman and Craig Bartholomew Strydom, to find out whether the rumoured death of American musician Sixto Rodriguez was true and, if not, to discover what had become of him.
Rodriguez's music, which had never achieved success in his home country of the United States, had
become very popular in South Africa, although little was known about him there.
On 10 February 2013, the film won the BAFTA Award for Best Documentary at the 66th British Academy Film Awards in London and
two weeks later, it won the Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature at the 85th Academy Awards in Hollywood.
The film explores themes of musician, 1970s, mayor, south africa, icon.